JESUS MANUEL ORTIZ

jesusmoh89@gmail.com | 786 630 5797 | www.linkedin.com/in/jesusmoh | Miami, FL 33134 | Visit my site

SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer with over a decade of experience in the IT field, specializing in Java Full Cycle development for more than seven years and expertise in Fintech, Retail, and IT Healthcare industries, where I have made significant contributions in roles such as Java Developer with cloud expertise and Java Full-Stack for Angular/Android. (I'm more than just a coder, I'm a problem solver).

HARD SKILLS

Java | Spring Cloud | JUnit | test-container | JMeter | JSP | SOLID | Git | Maven | Jira | Android | AWS | API design | SDKs | Cloud | ELK | Microservices | Ngnix | JS | EC2 | Angular | DevOps | Confluence | Database Design | SQL | NoSQL | MVC | JakartaEE | S3 | Kubernetes | Docker | Linux | Docker-Compose | Hyper-V | RAID | ETL | VSCode | PCI | Serverless | TypeScript | J2EE.

SOFT SKILLS

Team Player | Multitasking | Self-Taught Learner | Effective Leadership in Small Teams | Tolerance

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FISERV (Global Fintech) | Senior Software Development Engineer (II) | Team size 5 | May 2021 - April 2024 | U.S.A

- **Developed Spring/Angular** solutions for payment processing, such as gateway-payments/switches and offered **top-tier assistance** for financial switching (transactions) among POS terminals, ATM, e-commerce, and financial authorizers with specifications REST, ISO8583, and SOAP.
- Optimized backup time for logs by 60%, bolstering data security and reducing potential system downtime.
- Implemented integration tests with Selenium, Junit, and Docker, resulting in a 40% decrease in production issues.
- In 2022, I contributed to Fiserv Uruguay's success in becoming <u>the first payment network, capturing over 50% of the Uruguayan</u> payments market across all ecosystems.
- As part of the FSwitchUY team, we prioritized maintaining robust solutions through continuous updates and timely resolution of
 <u>critical security issues</u>. This, combined with other key objectives, enabled the company's sustained growth.

SISNET (Software Provider for Retail) | Senior Software Development Engineer | Team size 6 | Nov 2017 - May 2021 | URU

- Implemented Java backend solutions (Rest/SOAP APIs) using Jakarta, Payara Micro, Cache and Hibernate resulting in a 40% improvement in API response time, and enhanced system POS terminal performance.
- Design a roadmap to upgrade and transform legacy monolithic to microlites and microservices.
- Achieved a <u>UI/UX for the Android mobile App</u> and admin panel resulting satisfaction and positive feedback.

SASA (Retail auto-parts) | IT technical leader & Senior Software Development Engineer | Team size 6 | Sep 2014 – Nov 2017 | CUB

- Configured and planned strategic infrastructure upgrades for 14 on-premises dependencies, delivering a highly available solution that leveraged Hyper-V, Active Directory, RAID, and HP ProLiant servers, achieving a 99.00% increase in system uptime.
- Developed a Java-based solution from the ground up to categorize 5 years of slow-moving inventory at the company, resulting in a cost reduction of \$500,000 by applying the Pareto principle.
- Achieved a 70% decrease in processing time for ETL tasks related to stock status processing using Pentaho and Scala to support parallel processing of large datasets.

EDUCATION

• Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering, Technological University of Havana (CUJAE), Cuba, September 2009 – July 2014

CERTIFICATIONS AND BADGES

AWS Certified Developer Associate | AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate | AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner | ACG Kubernetes & Terraform | AWS DynamoDB Deep Dive.

OUTSIDE EXPERIENCE AND INITIATIVES

PHP | WooCommerce | Wix | Node.js | AI/ML | HL7 | HCE | PCI | GraalVM | Kotlin | Shopizer | GCP | Pentaho | Scala